{
  "question_and_answer": [
  {
      "question": "What is the full form of NUCAT?",
      "answer": "Nitte University Common Admission Test. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How do I apply for NUCAT?",
      "answer": "Register your application online on apply.nitte.edu.in. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Is there an application fee for NUCAT?",
      "answer": "A non-refundable fee of Rs. 1100/- has to be paid through Credit Card / Debit Card / Net Banking / UPI Payment Modes etc. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Will the registration fee be refunded if I do not take the Test?",
      "answer": "No. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "When is the last date for registering for NUCAT?",
      "answer": "NUCAT will be conducted in 3 phases. Please go through the Schedule on nucat.nitte.edu.in. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "I need to make corrections / modifications in my NUCAT application form. How can I do it?",
      "answer": "Any correction required in the application form, may be emailed to info@nitte.edu.in within 2 days of registration. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the pattern of NUCAT?",
      "answer": "40 questions each from Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics sections i.e. a total of 120 questions of 1 mark each to be answered in 120 minutes. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many times can I attempt NUCAT?",
      "answer": "A candidate can write the Test a maximum of 3 times, on payment of Registration Fee for each Test. Highest score will be considered for the ranking. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Where can I find the Question Bank of NUCAT?",
      "answer": "Question bank is not provided as this is only the third year of NUCAT. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the syllabus for NUCAT?",
      "answer": "The syllabus will be equivalent to that of Class 11 & 12 CBSE / State Board curriculum. The syllabus is provided in detail on nucat.nitte.edu.in. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Is there any negative marking in NUCAT?",
      "answer": "No. There is no negative marking. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How is the Rank decided in case of a tie?",
      "answer": "In case more than one candidate secures the same total marks, inter-se-merit will be determined on the basis of section scores in the following order: 1. Physics 2. Mathematics 3. Chemistry If there is a tie even after considering the section scores, inter-se-merit will be determined on the basis of Class 10 marks in the following order. 1. Science 2. Mathematics. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I qualify for admission to BTech through CET/COMEDK?",
      "answer": "No. NUCAT is the only Entrance Test for admission to BTech at NMAMIT. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Do you have any management / reservation/ donation quota?",
      "answer": "No. Besides General category, we have an Inclusivity category where 10% seats are earmarked for students who have passed Class 12 in India but outside the State of Karnataka. These students are also required to take NUCAT. In addition, we have the NRI category which is open to PIOs / Foreign Nationals / Students who have passed Class 12 abroad / Students who have passed Class 12 in India but sponsored by NRI parents or blood relatives. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How do I process for NRI category admission?",
      "answer": "Students can submit the NRI application available on apply.nitte.edu.in. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I avail any scholarships?",
      "answer": "Nitte University offers Freeships amounting to full waiver of tuition fee for B.Tech aspirants on a merit-cum-means basis as per AICTEâ€™s Tuition Fee Waiver (TFW) Scheme subject to fulfilling all the conditions laid down by the University. All Government scholarships and Community-based organisations sponsored scholarships can also be availed, if eligible. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How will I come to know if I am allotted a seat?",
      "answer": "The NUCAT Rank will be announced on the Test platform (nucat.codetantra.com). In-person Counselling will be conducted at N.M.A.M. Institute of Technology, Nitte for filling the seats in each of the programs, based on the NUCAT 2024 Ranks. The dates, schedule and procedural details for counselling will be announced on the website nucat.nitte.edu.in. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the amount payable to confirm the admission?",
      "answer": "Annual fee for the allotted program will have to be paid for confirmation of admission on the date of counselling. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What if I want to withdraw from my confirmed admission?",
      "answer": "Students are required to report at the college for cancellation of seat & refund of fee. A processing fee of Rs. 10,000/- will be deducted from the fee paid for withdrawal up to 30 days from the date of class commencement. No refund can be claimed after 30 days of class commencement. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Will I be able to upgrade my branch, if there are vacancies?",
      "answer": "Yes. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Will Class 12 marks be considered while allotting the ranks in NUCAT?",
      "answer": "No. Ranking is based on NUCAT score. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Do I need to download any app for the Test?",
      "answer": "Yes. You will be informed about the same after registration via email (support@codetantra.com). For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Whom should I contact if I am unable to download the Secure Exam App?",
      "answer": "For technical support regarding NUCAT: Telephone: +91 7995417777 / +91 6305007479 / +91 6305008997, E-mail: support@codetantra.com. You may also contact +91 8147837382 or nucat@nitte.edu.in. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Where do I get my Admit Card?",
      "answer": "e-Admit Card can be downloaded from your Test platform nucat.codetantra.com immediately after slot booking. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I change the timing of Test slot booked?",
      "answer": "No. Slot once booked cannot be changed. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I take the Test without booking the slot?",
      "answer": "A candidate cannot take the Test without a confirmed Test slot booking. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I use mobile phone instead of laptop for attending NUCAT?",
      "answer": "The Test must be taken through a laptop/desktop as primary device. In addition, either a Tablet or a Smart phone must be used as secondary device, as 3rd Eye. Both these devices must be connected to the internet throughout the exam. Kindly refer the NUCAT Information Bulletin for detailed information regarding technical requirement. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Is it compulsory to use 3rd Eye?",
      "answer": "Yes. It is compulsory to use Mobile / Tablet connected with internet, as 3rd Eye. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Should I sit in a closed room for Test?",
      "answer": "Yes. Candidates should take the Test in a well illuminated closed room which is free from external noise or disturbances. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I write the Test in Windows 7?",
      "answer": "Windows 10 or more is preferred. Please refer NUCAT Information Bulletin for detailed information regarding technical requirement. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "When should I login to the Test platform for taking NUCAT Test?",
      "answer": "Candidates should login 30 minutes before the Test. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Is writing the Mock test mandatory?",
      "answer": "Yes. For aspirants attempting the Remotely Proctored Online Test, both Human Proctored and AI Proctored Mock Tests are mandatory. For those opting for the Center Based Online Test, the Mock Test is optional, but it is recommended for the familiarity with the test and campus. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "When can I take the AI-proctored Mock Test?",
      "answer": "Candidates will be provided two Mock Tests - Mock Test 1 which is Human proctored and Mock Test 2 which is Machine proctored, before the Actual Test, to acclimatise themselves with the Test Taking procedure. The dates and details of the Human proctored mock test will be communicated through the e-Admit Card based on the Test slots booked by the candidates. The AI proctored mock test can be taken any time starting 5 days before the human proctored mock test until one day before the Actual Test. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I use rough sheet during the NUCAT Test?",
      "answer": "Yes. You can use only one blank A4 sheet during the Test and the same should be shown to the proctor before taking the Test. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What should I carry for the Test?",
      "answer": "Irrespective of Online or Centre based online test, the candidates are informed to mandatorily carry any valid Government Id Proof and e-Admit Card. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can the Test be taken from my college Lab?",
      "answer": "No. The Test cannot be taken from your college lab as it is not a Test Centre. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I take the Test from my parents work place/Cyber-Centre/ my balcony/living room?",
      "answer": "No. The Test should be taken in a well illuminated closed room which is free from external noise or disturbances. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Where are the Test Centres located?",
      "answer": "The Test Centres are located at: 1. NMAM Institute of Technology, Nitte, SH1, Karkala, Karnataka 574110 2. Nitte Meenakshi Institute of Technology, 6429, NITTE Meenakshi College Rd, BSF Campus, Yelahanka, Bengaluru, Govindapura, Karnataka 560064 3. Nitte Institute of Professional Education, near Nitte Institute of Hospitality Services, Kodakal, Mangaluru, Karnataka 575007 4. KS Hegde Medical Academy, P.O. Nityanandanagar, Deralakatte, Mangaluru, Karnataka 575018 5. Nitte Institute of Communication, Paneer, Kotekar-Beeri Road, P.O Deralakatte, Kotekar, Karnataka 575018. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How do I change the mode of NUCAT Test from Online to a Test Centre?",
      "answer": "Candidates should send a request email to nucat@nitte.edu.in. Facility will be provided subject to availability. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What are the things I should bring to the Test Centre if I am appearing for the Test at the Centre?",
      "answer": "Candidates are informed to mandatorily carry original Aadhaar card / any valid Government Id Proof, printed copy of e-Admit Card and a pen to work out problems. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Do I need a hard copy of the e-Admit card for Mock Test?",
      "answer": "Yes. Candidates should keep a printed copy of the e-Admit card and original Aadhar card/ any valid Government Id Proof for appearing for Mock Test as well as Actual Test. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I use the calculator?",
      "answer": "Candidates are not permitted to use a physical calculator. Virtual calculator will be provided on the Test platform (nucat.codetantra.com). For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How do I sort any issues occurring during NUCAT Test?",
      "answer": "You can call your proctor or communicate through the screen. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What if my laptop or mobile goes off due to low charge during the Test?",
      "answer": "There is nothing much that can be done in this regard. Hence, please ensure that your Laptop and Mobile / Tablet is fully charged before taking the Test. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How do I get my Mock Test result?",
      "answer": "Mock Test is not evaluated. It is conducted to help the Test taker familiarise himself / herself with the Test procedures. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What are the college timings?",
      "answer": "From 9:00 AM to 4:30 PM. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the average class size at NMAMIT?",
      "answer": "Sixty (60). For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the minimum attendance required in NMAMIT?",
      "answer": "Students should have 85% attendance in each semester to be eligible to write the semester examinations. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I know more about the hostel facilities in the campus?",
      "answer": "Hostel facilities include separate blocks for first-year students, TV room, recreation room, indoor stadium/gymnasium, cricket, hockey, football ground, water coolers & RO purifiers, scheduled hot water supply for bath, generator with 500 KVA & 160KVA, laundry, veg & non-veg, North & South Indian mess, celebration of various festivals, academic guidance in the hostel after working hours of college, ambulance/subsidized healthcare. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Is it compulsory to stay in hostel?",
      "answer": "No. However, staying in the campus enables students to make the best use of their time and facilities available. Campus life helps students prepare for their professional career. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Will I get hostel accommodation at the time of admission?",
      "answer": "Yes. Hostel accommodation can be booked at the time of admission. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Are we required to pay the hostel fee along with the college fee?",
      "answer": "If hostel accommodation is required, hostel fee will have to be paid at the time of admission. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I know the Hostel Fee structure?",
      "answer": "The hostel fee structure is available on the website www.nitte.edu.in under Program fee. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What are the options available for food in the campus?",
      "answer": "Hygienic North Indian and South Indian food is served in the hostels. Besides this, there are 2 canteens, 3 cafeterias as well as Fast Food joints on campus which are featured in Restaurant Guru. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Are bus facilities available for day scholars?",
      "answer": "Yes. Bus facilities are available at subsidized rates. The College has a fleet of buses for students and staff from Karkala, Mangaluru, Udupi, Hebri, Karkala town, etc. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Will there be any extra charges for the bus facilities?",
      "answer": "Yes. Nominal charges are levied as bus fees. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How can I pay my college and hostel fees?",
      "answer": "Fees can be paid online through the NMAMIT website (www.nitte.edu.in). For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I pay the fees in installments?",
      "answer": "Yes. Fees can be paid in installments. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Is there any fine for late payment of fees?",
      "answer": "Yes. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Do you provide any financial assistance or scholarships?",
      "answer": "Yes, we provide Freeships as per AICTE norms. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Can I know about the placement facilities at NMAMIT?",
      "answer": "NMAMIT has an excellent placement record with many students being placed in reputed companies every year. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "What are the companies that visit NMAMIT for placements?",
      "answer": "Companies like Infosys, Wipro, TCS, Tech Mahindra, Capgemini, Cerner, ITC Infotech, HP, SAP Labs, Siemens, etc., visit NMAMIT for placements. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Is there any entrepreneurship cell at NMAMIT?",
      "answer": "Yes. NMAMIT has an Entrepreneurship Development Cell (EDC) which encourages students to develop entrepreneurial skills and start their ventures. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "Are there any clubs or student societies on campus?",
      "answer": "Yes. There are various clubs and student societies on campus including technical, cultural, and sports clubs. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  },
  {
      "question": "How can I get in touch with the college administration for further information?",
      "answer": "You can contact the college administration through the following means: Phone: +91 8258254801, Email: info@nitte.edu.in. For more information please visit the following link https://nucat.nitte.edu.in/"
  }
]
}
